

I am an experienced and highly motivated manager with years of experience in leading projects and managing resources to implement change and deliver significant business value to both internal and external partners. I have a proven track-record of using my communication and collaborative skills to successfully design, manage and implement major IT projects within a corporate environment at both local and national levels.

As a candidate, I provide a rare combination of collaborative skills, project management experience and technical expertise. I am the ideal link between project stakeholders; able to use agile and plan-driven methodologies to mediate between project owners and technical resources to collaborate, design, implement and deliver projects effectively, within budget, to specification and on-time.

### **SKILLS**

Team-work & collaboration	Effective communication	Leadership
Project management	Critical analysis	Change management
Process improvement	Technical understanding	Software engineering
Business championship	Complex problem-solving	Agile methodologies

# **EDUCATION**

GLOBAL KNOWLEDGE	ITIL: FOUNDATION	05/2015
QUEEN'S UNIVERSITY, BELFAST	MSC. SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT	09/2013 - 2018 (TBC)
OUFFN'S UNIVERSITY BELFAST	BTH THEOLOGY HONS (2:1)	09/2009 - 06/2013

# **EXPERIENCE**

IT MANAGEMENT GRADUATE	LLOYDS BANKING GROUP	09/2014 - 07/2017
PMO ANALYST, SME	ADM: CROSS PRODUCT	09/2014 - 03/2015

Reporting directly to the HoF, I worked with the Cross Product Leadership to construct the 2015 Project Portfolio and get a better view of resource allocation for the team. I championed one of the Group's One Best Way tools across the function and helped identify a major issue with one of the Group's external partners. I also championed and helped implement a new suite of cloud-based productivity tools from IBM, one of our major software partners.

During my placement, I recognised a major issue in the function's internal reporting systems. I took the initiative, and got approval from the HoF to develop, test and implement an automated Supply and Demand template, enabling managers to get an accurate view of hot/cold spots, on demand, based on the latest data automatically pulled from internal systems and other sources. This report had previously needed to be compiled manually, provided a view only once a week, and took an employee an entire workday to complete. My solution reduced the process to two clicks and 30 seconds of computation, enabling any senior manager to get an instant live-view of crucial MI.

I worked directly with the HoF, taking ownership of several projects delegated to me within the Channel Islands. Alongside successfully implementing several new processes, both local and Islands-wide, I was responsible for championing both Learning and Recognition initiatives, improving uptake of available training resources.

In response to an internal dissatisfaction with our colleague recognition systems, I interviewed all members of the team and worked with the HoF, using that feedback to independently develop and implement a brand-new Recognition portal for colleagues to use. This new internal site streamlined roughly five seperate systems into a 'one-stop' site and quartered the amount of steps required to recognise fellow colleagues for exceptional performance. The portal was implemented islands-wide and caused a dramatic increase in submissions, improving recognition efforts for the entire function.

**EXECUTIVE ASSISTANT** 

### **COMMUNITY BANK SYSTEMS**

09/2015 - 03/2016

My third role was as Executive Assistant to the Director of Group IT Community Bank Systems. This function was responsible for the development, delivery and maintenance of all the major IT systems implemented within all of the branches of LBG's various brands.

The Director delegated many of her responsibilities to me. Not only did I assist her directly with the leadership of the function, working with her other direct reports, but I was also entrusted with leading a major cost-saving project on her behalf. I was also responsible for running many of the weekly MI meetings, as well as personally organising and scheduling the monthly senior management meetings across the country.

### INNOVATION ARCHITECT

AMI: INNOVATION

03/2016 - 07/2017

My fourth role was as an Innovation Architect within the Innovation function of the Bank. Responsibilities included researching, implementing and demonstrating new technologies with a focus on blockchain, IoT and AI.

This placement was more practical in nature than the others, in that I had to personally evaluate bleeding-edge innovations at a technical level to gauge functionality, utility and potential business value. I then had to create repeatable technical demos to be shown to the directors of Lloyds Banking Group, who would then choose which technologies to fund and progress toward larger-scale pilots within the Bank.

While this role was largely evangelical in nature, it was also my responsibility to reduce unnecessary expenditure on technologies that were either unready, misrepresented or overvalued. This required constant judgement and risk evaluation, as the Bank needed the right balance between remaining competitive and ensuring R&D expenditure was within reasonable limits.